<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>go on @FollowTheProcess</title>
    <link>https://followtheprocess.github.io/tags/go/</link>
    <description>Recent content in go on @FollowTheProcess</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 19:04:46 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://followtheprocess.github.io/tags/go/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Shut Down a Go HTTP Server Gracefully</title>
      <link>https://followtheprocess.github.io/posts/graceful_shutdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Oct 2021 19:04:46 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://followtheprocess.github.io/posts/graceful_shutdown/</guid>
      <description>When developing HTTP services in Go, you will start and stop your server hundreds of times, think of the whole go run main.go ctrl + c loop!
When you hit ctrl + c, (on UNIX systems) your program is passed the SIGINT Unix signal. The go runtime handles this and will stop your program relatively safely, but it&amp;rsquo;s not great practice!
What if you have database connection pools open or forgot to close a file etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using FieldsFunc in Go</title>
      <link>https://followtheprocess.github.io/posts/fieldsfunc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Oct 2021 20:34:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://followtheprocess.github.io/posts/fieldsfunc/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing with Go a lot recently, and one thing it lends itself really well to is CLIs (Command Line Interfaces):
Runs very fast, feels snappy to use Standalone, statically linked binary - easy to distribute Easy cross-compilation for multiple platforms, OS&amp;rsquo;s and processor architectures Excellent libraries for creating CLIs e.g. cobra The excellent GitHub CLI is written in Go 👏🏻
So needless to say, I&amp;rsquo;ve been writing more than a few CLIs: gotoil, tag, goignore etc&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>goignore</title>
      <link>https://followtheprocess.github.io/projects/goignore/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://followtheprocess.github.io/projects/goignore/</guid>
      <description>An extremely simple go CLI to hit the gitignore API with whatever you pass as command line arguments. The list of things you can pass here are documented on gitignore.io.
Source Code: https://github.com/FollowTheProcess/goignore You&amp;rsquo;ll get back a .gitignore file saved to $CWD/.gitignore with the contents generated from the API.
Installation go install github.com/FollowTheProcess/goignore@latest Usage Inside the folder you want the .gitignore to live in, run:
goignore macos visualstudiocode go This will get you a .</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
