<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>engineering on @FollowTheProcess</title>
    <link>https://followtheprocess.github.io/tags/engineering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in engineering on @FollowTheProcess</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://followtheprocess.github.io/tags/engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>pymechtest</title>
      <link>https://followtheprocess.github.io/projects/pymechtest/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://followtheprocess.github.io/projects/pymechtest/</guid>
      <description>pymechtest is a small, hopefully helpful python package to help engineers collate, process, analyse, and report on mechanical test data. I built pymechtest to help automate the things I did on a near-daily basis as a materials engineer. I hope it can prove some use to you too!
Source Code: https://github.com/FollowTheProcess/pymechtest
Documentation: https://FollowTheProcess.github.io/pymechtest/
Overview Have you ever had to process a bunch of csv output from a mechanical test machine, copying and pasting data into a hacky Excel template to calculate things like elastic modulus and yield strength?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fatigue Damage Prediction</title>
      <link>https://followtheprocess.github.io/projects/fatigue/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://followtheprocess.github.io/projects/fatigue/</guid>
      <description>Using machine learning to predict fatigue crack growth under complex thermomechanical loads. Achieved a damage severity predicive accuracy of ±0.25mm and a positional predictive accuracy of ±7.0mm.
Tom Fleet, Sep 2020
Background Repeated cyclic loading of a material will eventually lead to a phenomenon called &amp;ldquo;fatigue crack growth&amp;rdquo;. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to explain the details here but I&amp;rsquo;d point you to this for more info. Essentially, a crack will start to form and repeated cyclic loading will progressively grow this crack until it is large enough such that the remaining material can no longer handle the stress and the component will break.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
